Guide to the Cornell Fraternity and Sorority Affairs Office records, 1960-2009.
Cornell Fraternity and Sorority Affairs Office records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Fraternity and Sorority Affairs Office records, 1960-2009.
37-4-3027
Cornell University. Fraternity and Sorority Affairs Office.
2.5 cubic ft.
Scrapbooks, photographs, correspondence, rush books, bylaws, annual reports, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes scrapbooks, photographs, correspondence, rush books, bylaws, annual reports, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and ephemera of fraternities and sororities at Cornell University. Also, t-shirt from Cornell Greek Week, 2003.
Annual reports from the Fraternity and Sorority Advisory Council, 1997-2009; Guide and Map of the Fraternities & Sororities, 2003-2009; and brochures.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes scrapbooks, photographs, correspondence, rush books, bylaws, annual reports, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and ephemera of fraternities and sororities at Cornell University. Also, t-shirt from Cornell Greek Week, 2003.
Annual reports from the Fraternity and Sorority Advisory Council, 1997-2009; Guide and Map of the Fraternities & Sororities, 2003-2009; and brochures.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Societies, etc.; Cornell University. Fraternity and Sorority Advisory Council.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.; Women college students.; Greek letter societies; Societies; Students; Women college students
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Bylaws (administrative records)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Fraternity and Sorority Affairs records
CONTAINER LIST
- Fraternity and Sorority Affairs records
  - NYSFDA Regional Fraternity Deans and IFC Presidential Conference correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Association of Fraternity Advisors Conference materials; Dr. Tom Fiutak correspondence and notes, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Also contains notes and conference materials from 1976 National Interfraternity Council meeting of the Board of Directors
  - Professional Association journals, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Journals and newsletters relating to counseling and guidance
  - Northeast Regional Inter Fraternity Conference materials and attendee worksheets, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - World's Largest Lasagna Fest permits and plans, correspondence, invoices, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Day correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A History of the Cornell University Housing Plans - 1890-1971" by David B. Henderson, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Also contains "Black Hats and White Hats: Polarization on the Campus" by David Henderson, dated 6 March 1970
  - Correspondence regarding Chi Phi house renovation and expenses, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspodence regarding Chi Phi entrance to Cornell University Residence Plan; also contains correspondence regarding Psi Upsilon suspension, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Also contains minutes of Chi Phi Chapter House Association annual meeting, 1968 and 1969
  - House President Meeting materials (1970); correspondence with house presidents (1975-1977), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Also contains Cesar Chavez letter requesting donations to Farm Workers Union, flyer on wines to boycott, and photocopies of New York Times articles regarding Chavez
  - Statements of fraternities' compliance with Saperston Report recommendation 5 regarding membership selection policy, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Also contains 1971 letter regarding Theta Delta Chi house fire hazards
  - Anti-discrimination materials, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Reports on 1966 Saperston Report and Recommendation 5; statements of fraternities' compliance with anti-discrimination policies; 1961 newspaper articles regarding Executive Board votes on anti-discrimination policies
  - Materials and correspondence regarding implementation of and revisions to Saperston Report Recommendation 5 on non-discrimination policies in fraternaties and sororities, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Materials and correspondence regarding implementation of and revisions to Saperston Report Recommendation 5 on non-discrimination policies in fraternaties and sororities, 1960-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Contains some documentation on anti-discrimination policies at other universities
  - Materials and correspondence regarding implementation of and revisions to Saperston Report Recommendation 5 on non-discrimination policies in fraternaties and sororities, 1960-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Post-commission correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and draft documentation regarding implementation of Saperston Report Recommendation 5, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Statements of fraternities' compliance with Recommendation 5 of the Report of the University Commission of Residential Environment, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cornell University Residence Plan documentation and correspondence, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Contains minutes of meetings of the Faculty Committee on Student Affairs
  - "Greek is the Word" Louisiana State University Panhellenic rush guide, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Panhellenic Conference Manual of Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A. D. White Leadership Conference program, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous fraternity and sorority photos, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Includes slides, Greek Week 1989, 1990-1991 Panhellenic Council, and sorority house composit photo sheet, and undated photos
  - Office of Fraternity and Sorority Affairs newsletters, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Greek system statistic sheets, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Greek Fellows Mentoring Program, Greek Life, and Creating Chapters of Excellence brochures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Interfraternity Council newsletter, 1950-01-13 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Janet Miller research on sorority pledge programs, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Janet Miller was a second-year student in the Master of Arts in Student Personnel Administration program in the 1964-1965 school year.
  - Mark Barlow Jr. correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Mark Barlow was Vice President for Student Affairs and later Vice Provost. Contains a copy of the Sterling Forest report on residential environment.
  - Mark Barlow Jr. correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Mark Barlow was Vice President for Student Affairs and later Vice Provost.
  - Sorority correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fraternity correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with national fraternity associations, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Much of the material relates to Title IX impact on fraternities
  - Fraternity judicial correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Interfraternity Council bylaws and violations, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Interfraternity Council bylaws and violations, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fraternity policies, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Contains research on history of fraternities, and copies of Muller Report
  - Fraternity complaint reports, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student Management Corporation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fraternity rush, 1967-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Interfraternity Council, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fraternity Newsletter;" National Interfraternity Conference "Campus Commentary"; Association of Fraternity Advisors correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Fraternity management, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes budgets, information on fraternity tax filing, and reports of national and international leadership
  - Special reports on fraternities, 1950-1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Includes 1964 Report on Student-Faculty Relationships at Cornell, Butler study, Hacker report, Cornell Fraternity Self-Study Program, Muller report, 1950 Cornell Student Questionnaire
  - Fraternity representatives and nationals correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Greek Columns" newspaper issues, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Greek Columns" newspaper issues, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Also includes Winter 1990 issue of "The Star and Lamp of Pi Kappa Phi" and August 1988 issue of "The Sigma Phi Epsilon Journal"
  - Fraternity newspaper and magazine clippings, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Includes 1963 Report on Fraternities at Cornell University
  - Fraternity clippings from Cornell Daily Sun, 1950-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence and materials relating to establishment of Alpha Gamma Sigma fraternity at Cornell, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes 1967 Constitution of the Alpha Chapter of Alpha Gamma Sigma Professional Agricultural Fraternity
  - Greek Week t-shirt, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Panhellenic Memories" scrapbook, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)